[Music]
oh
amen happy Sabbath church family um I
want to welcome you again to living Mana
online church and uh we are gonna jump
straight into this message today now
today's message is really going to be
kind of short but to the point
so uh go ahead you all and uh share this
link let people know that this is on let
people know not building up to anything
we're jumping right into this thing so
we're going to pray put a one in the
chat uh if you are ready to get into the
word of God and uh let's let's get into
this we got a lot to cover um let's ask
for the Lord to guide us as we go
through his word let's pray Heavenly
Father please speak to us Lord as we
open your word Lord we need to hear a
word from you Lord um help us to
understand what is going on around us
help us to understand how to be
prepared and Lord open our eyes that we
may see as our prayer in Jesus name amen
amen uh today's sermon beloved is
entitled is entitled Barabas the problem
with modern-day
Christianity the problem with modern day
Christianity I'm going to go right to
the screen and uh I want to start off
with Revelation chapter
13 Revelation chapter 13
beginning with verse 11 the Bible says
and I beheld another Beast coming up out
of the earth and he had two horns like a
lamb and he spake as a dragon and he
exerciseth all the power of the first
Beast before him and cause the Earth and
them that dwell therein to worship the
first Beast whose deadly wound was
healed in the Bible we understand that a
beast in Prophecy is symbolic
of a Nation thus we're looking at a
nation that has a lambl likee appearance
but speaks like a dragon all we need to
do is go to the scriptures and we will
see that in the
Bible according to the Book of John
chapter 1 verse
29 the lamb is a symbol of Jesus the
Bible says the next day John seeth Jesus
coming unto him and saith
Behold the Lamb of God which taketh away
away the sin of the world the lamb in
the Bible is symbolic of Jesus and
therefore this nation that the Bible is
describing that has the horns of a lamb
but speaks as a dragon would represent a
professed Christian Nation which Bible
students will recognize that this is
speaking of none other than than uh um
than the United States of
America um what we know as
protestantism specifically in the nation
of America the Bible says that this
entity protestantism particularly in
America would exercise the power of the
first Beast before
him and so the question is who is the
first Beast
before this Beast the first Beast
according to Revelation 13:1 is a beast
that resembled a lion a bear a leopard
and a dragon which we understand
according to Bible prophecy according to
the Book of Daniel chapter 7 where these
beasts are mentioned uh in order Babylon
meter Persia Greece Rome followed by a
little
horn that would rule for 1,260 years we
understand that this power represents
the papal system now here is where I
want you to pay attention and really to
focus because the Bible says that the
the second beast
exercise the power of the first Beast
now the power of the first Beast is that
it was a church State
entity and and and in order for us to to
understand the significance of what
we're seeing in today's society we
simply have to ask a question how did
the first Beast get its power because
we're told that the second beast will
exercise the same power meaning that the
second beast must also get that same
power so we need to understand how did
the first Beast get its power how did
the papal system how did the Church of
the Dark Ages get its power well if you
go back in history you will see that the
early church had been persecuted by the
Roman Empire the Roman Empire was a
secular Empire the Roman Empire um was
an Empire that was against
Christianity and Christians were being
persecuted uh uh and and and you know
killed in coliseums fed to the Lions uh
just all kinds of horrendous things
happening to the Christians so this is
uh the first century the second century
and then something very very interesting
happened in the third Century something
happened where um or I should say the
4th Century something happened where a a
man by by the name of
Constantine um
became a champion for
Christianity so around
321 ad uh we find some very significant
things happening but I want to read here
from the book entitled the change of the
Sabbath page 114 written by GI Butler
here's what he says mosim places the
nominal conversion of Constantine two
years later than the edict we say
nominal conversion for there is no good
reason to believe that he was ever a
genuine Christian he was a tyrant a
murderer of many innocent persons and
gave evidence of being anything but a
follower of the prince of
peace and
so when Constantine became
converted he basically
elevated Christianity to a to a level a
political level that they had not
experienced
before and this lay the
foundation this lay the
groundwork for the beginning of papal
domination that would last over a
thousand
years and so please note that it was a
it was a a person that really wasn't
converted but the Christians looked at
this individual as their
Champion to to Champion
Christianity this lay the
foundation for the papacy to become
dominant over Kings over the kings of
the earth so put a one uh in the chat uh
if you are following what I'm saying
thus far we know
then that this second beast will also
receive its power in like manner
the second beast will ultimately realize
a
unification of church and state that's
what the prophecy is telling us about
this second beast this this Beast that
has the horns of a lamb looks Christian
but speaks like a dragon and so now that
we've laid the foundation of what we can
expect to see in America yay what we are
in fact already seeing in America
because there is a movement of foot that
has
been in the
works for this rise of Christian
nationalism but I want to pause right
here for a moment and what we need to do
right now is we need to go back to the
days of Jesus and and I'm going to show
you something that that hopefully will
give us greater insight into what we see
happening today so um let's go to the
The Book of John 11:48 and first I want
to demonstrate to you the attitude of
the Jews in the days of Jesus so the
Bible says
here um in John
11:48 if we let him thus
Salone all men will believe on him and
the Romans shall come and take away both
our place and
Nation so this is the these are the the
the Pharisees that are speaking here and
um I want you to note their
concern they're talking about Jesus if
we leave him alone he's really going to
mess things up for us and ultimately our
greatest fears are going to be realized
and what were their greatest
fears that the Romans would come and
take away their place meaning their
Sanctuary their place of worship and
their Nation so the the key concern of
the Jews in the days of Jesus the
Pharisees in the days of Jesus was their
position as a church and as a political
entity as a
nation we are worried about the Romans
destroying our worship and our nation so
so they were concerned highly concerned
about two things worship and the state
of their Nation let's add three things
worship the their worship the state of
their nation and the Godless enemy of
the Roman
Empire all right so again I'm going to
ask you to go ahead and put a one in the
chat if you are following the train of
thought the
Jews in the days of
Jesus feared
the Godless Roman
Empire that the Godless Roman Empire
would
destroy their worship and their Nation
all right so that was their concern and
they were so concerned about it
that they were willing to get rid of
Jesus in order to preserve their worship
and their Nation y'all follow what I
just
said there in this text they're actually
talking about we probably need to get
rid of
Jesus that's what they're talking
about why because if we don't get rid of
him if we don't move him out of the way
our worship is going to be affected and
our nation is going to be affected by
the Godless enemies okay so so I wanted
to just paint a picture of the
mentality of the Believers in the days
of Jesus
the mentality of the
believer in the days of
Jesus so let's go back to the
screen and um we're going to go to
Matthew 12 verse 18 the Bible says here
behold my servant whom I have chosen my
beloved in whom I my soul is well
pleased I will put my spirit upon him
and he shall show judgment to the
Gentiles now pretty straight forward
verse but there's an issue with this
verse because the Jews of Jesus's day
would have been highly troubled by this
verse you see in the New Testament in
fact in the gospels uh the term Gentile
or even the term Rome or
Romans is
used somewhere between
15 16 maybe 17 times all together that
is in Matthew Mark Luke and
John and every time the term is used so
I want you to think Romans would be the
equivalent today of just think think
atheist think Godless right think
whatever term you you would think of
that is H against
Christianity um that is allegedly
against Christianity think of those
things in in today's society that would
be oh the
secular government right that's who the
Romans are and again it's mention a
total of of somewhere between 15 to 18
times between Matthew Mark Luke and John
but but most of the times that the term
Gentile Gentiles or or Rome is used
listen to this Jesus when he uses
it it's not
saying what the Jews may have wanted to
hear
for example the text on the
screen I will put my spirit upon him
that is Jesus and he will show judgment
to the Gentiles what he will show
judgment to the Gentiles wait you're
trying to help the Gentiles Jesus I
don't know if we're too down with that
Jesus you're trying to show judgment to
the you're trying to show the Gentile
the difference between right and wrong
no no no no the Gentiles are our
enemies why are you showing judgment to
why are you why are you showing them
truth why are you being aik to them
that's not what we want to hear let's go
back to the
screen Matthew
12:21 and in his name shall the Gentiles
trust wa wait wait wait wait wait wait
wait
what why no we don't want the Gentiles
trusting in your name Jesus the Gentiles
are our enemies don't you don't you see
don't you understand the Romans are our
enemies what what what are we talking
about in his name shall the Gentiles
trust you can see so put a one in the
chat if you can see how the Jews in
Christ
day could have
been pretty much upset with him that his
attitude towards the
Gentiles wasn't what they were looking
for let's go back to the screen again
want you to want you to notice
again um here's an incident where Jesus
has just finished feeding many people
and the Bible says in John 6 ver 13 and
14 therefore they gathered them together
that is the fragments of bread and
filled 12 baskets with the fragments of
the five barley loaves which remained
over and above unto them that had eaten
then those men when they had seen the
miracle that Jesus did said this is of a
truth the that Prophet that should come
into the world so now they're like whoa
this guy's a Prophet this is the this is
whoa this is who the Bible's been
talking about and then notice what the
next text
says when Jesus therefore
perceived that they would come and take
him by force to make him a king he
departed again into a mountain himself
alone now let's pause pause for a
second why do you think the
people now they didn't say let's make
him King the Bible says Jesus in essence
read their hearts he knew where their
hearts
were and he knew what they were thinking
we're going to take this man by force if
necessary to make him King why because
he's got Supernatural power he's got
Supernatural power and if he has
Supernatural power and we make him our
King then we're going to have a
chance to
defeat our political enemies the Roman
Empire y'all put a five in the
chat put a five in the chat if you
follow what I'm
saying they wanted
Jesus to deliver them
from their
political
enemies are y'all with me are you with
me let's let's let's keep reading in
John chapter 6 ver 25 so this is several
verses later uh Jesus leaves and then
many go and follow him to where he is
and then they find him the Bible says in
verse 25 and when they had found him on
the other side of the sea they said unto
him Rabbi when CEST thou Jesus answered
them and said verily verily I say unto
you you seek me not because you saw the
Miracles but because you did eat of the
Loaves and were filled all right so
let's break this
down Jesus is telling them the reason
you're looking after the reason you're
coming after me the reason you're
following me right now is not because of
the miracle the Divine things you saw
but because
you were
filled your temporal needs and desires
were
met and now you want me to be that
provider of your temporal needs that's
what he's telling them he's saying you
didn't seek me because of the Miracles
you sought me because of what you got in
Return of my Mir you're you're seeking
me because
I
satisfied a temporal need of yours and
now you're thinking man if we had him
around man he could fill my bank if we
had him around man he could make me
prosperous if we had him around man he
could do all these things for me and
Elevate me even above my
enemies that's what Jesus is telling
them he's saying you're looking after me
and I want you to think for a moment how
many people do you think are seeking
Jesus not because of the miracle he does
in providing the bread of life for us
but because they
desire to be
filled in temporal
Goods they
Desiring to be
delivered from political
enemies instead of
the as Terry likes to say the inner me
the
enemy the
ennery they weren't interested in that
they wanted
Deliverance they wanted
deliverance from their political enemies
they wanted deliverance from poverty
they wanted deliverance from hard times
they wanted deliverance from from from
what they felt was government oppression
that's what they wanted
notice what Jesus says verse 52 same
same incident verse
52 the Jews therefore strove among
themselves saying how can this man give
us his flesh to
eat then Jesus said unto them verily
verily I say unto you except you eat the
Flesh of the son of man and drink his
blood you have no life in you what he's
telling them is look y'all are thinking
about the temporal bread and I'm telling
you that I'm here to give you spiritual
bread but you are so focused on your
temporal wants and needs and desires
your desires of of of making me King to
dominate your enemies that you are
missing the point alt together and so he
goes on verse 64 whoo eateth my flesh
and drinketh my blood has eternal life
and I will raise him up at the last day
for my flesh is meat indeed and my blood
is drink indeed he that eateth my flesh
and drinketh my blood dwelleth in me and
I in him and and as the living father
has sent me and I live by the father so
he that eateth me even he shall live by
me this is that bread which came down
from
heaven not as your fathers did eat mana
and are dead but he that eateth of of
this bread shall live forever these
things he said in the synagogue as he
taught in Capernaum NOW Watch What
Happens Next go with me to verse
16 many therefore of his disciples when
they had heard it heard this said this
is a hard saying who can hear it when
Jesus knew in himself that his disciples
murmured at it he said unto them does
this offend you what if you shall see
the son of man ascending up where he was
before it is the spirit that quickeneth
the flesh profiteth nothing the words
that I speak unto you they are spirit
and they are life but there are some of
you that believe not you're following me
but you believe not you want temporal
relief but you believe not your father
you want to make me King but you don't
really believe in me for Jesus knew from
the beginning who they were that believ
not and who should betray him and he
said therefore said I unto you that no
man can come unto me except it were
given unto him of my father and from
that time many of his disciples went
backward and walked no more with
him now let's pause for a
moment cuz we're going somewhere with
this I want you to note
here that these were the same people
people that wanted to make him King they
wanted deliverance from their Roman
oppressors but when Jesus is like hey
that's not my message I'm not coming to
to destroy the Gentiles I'm not coming
to overthrow this political system
that's not what I've come to do I'm
coming to coming to give you the bread
of life and they were
like no thank
you we
good we are good you are not the type of
deliverer that we're looking for you're
not we want a deliverer but you're not
it because your methods are just not not
love the Gentiles
nah we need
somebody we need somebody that's gonna
get things
done come with me to the the the book
desire Ages page
391 let's see what elen white says about
this this very
chapter Christ had spoken a sacred
Eternal truth regarding the relation
between himself and his followers he
knew the character of those who claimed
to be his disciples and his words tested
their faith he declared that they were
to believe and act upon his teaching all
who should receive him would partake of
his nature and be conformed to his
character this involved the Rel the
relinquishment of their cherished
Ambitions it required the complete
surrender of themselves to Jesus they
were called to become self-sacrificing
meek and lowly in heart they must walk
in the narrow path traveled by the man
of Calvary if they should share in the
gift of life and the glory of Heaven the
test was too great The enthusiasm of
those who had sought to take him by
force and make him King grew
cold this discourse in the synagogue
they declared had opened their
eyes now they were
undeceived in their minds his words were
a direct confession that he was not the
Messiah and that no earthly rewards were
to be realized from
connection with him
wow wow they had welcomed his Miracle
working power for they were eager to be
freed from disease
and suffering but they would not come
into sympathy with his self
sacrificing
life they cared not for the spiritual
things of the
Kingdom yeah not for the spiritual
things not for the spiritual Kingdom of
which he spoke now they didn't care
about that the insincere the selfish
whom he whom who had sought him no
longer desired him if he would not
devote now please I'mma read this
slow if he would not devote his power
and influence to obtaining their freedom
from the
Romans they would have nothing to
do with
him okay
y'all give me give me uh give me a five
in the
chat
if y'all understand what's going on
here I I probably don't even need to
finish the sermon but I will and I
must they didn't want a
Jesus that was all about heart
transformation n no no they needed a
Jesus who was going to
go not into the church and overturn
tables why you overturning tables in the
church Jesus we need you to overturn
tables in the government the Roman
government that's the Jesus we want not
the Jesus that is coming to rebuke us we
need you to go rebuke the true
enemies the Roman government stop
throwing over
tables stop overturning tables in the
church we need you to go to the real
enemies to the real bad guys we need you
to go to the marxists and the Communists
and the global Elites and the government
and and the the Romans and
overthrow their
tables that's what we need you to do so
Jesus are you going to do that or
not are you going to do that or not
what's it going to be Jesus so when they
realize that Jesus is like that's not
what I'm about that's not what I came to
do I didn't come to overthrow
governments I came to overthrow Hearts I
didn't come to conquer governments I
came to conquer Hearts when they
realized that the Bible says they walk
with him no more but trust me they still
wanted the same thing they still that
walking away from him didn't mean that
in their own minds they weren't still
Believers yeah they're still Believers
we believe in
God and we believe that God's going to
send us someone who is going going to
overthrow the government come with me
come with me back to the
screen Matthew
27:15 now at the feast the governor was
want to release unto the people a
prisoner whom they
would they
then and they had then a notable
prisoner
called
Barabas Barabas
let's see here
um yep here we go Matthew
27:17 therefore when they were gathered
together pilate said unto them whom will
ye that I release unto you Barabas or
Jesus which is called Christ now the
interesting thing here is that in the
lexum English Bible Matthew 27:16 this
same verse it reads at that time they
had a notable prisoner named Jesus
Barabas
Jesus
Barabas now let's talk about
Barabas his name was
Jesus
Barabas what does that name mean
Jesus he shall save the people from his
sin
Jesus bar abas bar son of Abba
Father so so now they've got two jesuses
standing before
them the
Jews the Believers in jesus' day had two
jesuses standing before them one was
Jesus Son of the father and the other
was Jesus Son of the
father Jesus Barabas son of the Father
and Jesus son of the father a and
they're now being asked choose which one
you want released unto
you choose which one you want released
unto you so they've got a choice now now
they look at Jesus the son of the father
and they're looking at Jesus and then
they're looking at Jesus the son of the
father they're like man what Jesus do we
want which Jesus do we which Jesus would
we rather yeah you know what but we
don't want the
Jesus that is talking about a heart
conversion no we don't want that we want
the other
Jesus why would why did they want the
other Jesus why did they want Barabas
why did they want that Jesus let me tell
you why let me show you what he was in
prison
for Mark
15:7 and there was one named Barabas
which lay bound with them that had
made Insurrection with him who had
committed
murder in the
Insurrection Luke 23 puts it this way
Luke 23:25 and he released unto
them him that for
sedition and murder was cast into prison
whom they had desired but he delivered
Jesus to their will all right so tell me
about Barabas what do we know about
Barabas just from just from this story
what we know about
Barabas what we know is
that barabus was an insurrectionist he
led an
Insurrection that's what he
did now what is an
Insurrection it is an
attack on the
government we want the
Jesus that will overthrow our political
enemies that's the J we want the Jesus
that's going to get things
done that's the Jesus we
want so now to
recap the Believers in the days of Jesus
did not want a
Jesus who was about heart
transformation that's not what they were
looking
for they wanted a
Jesus that would lead a
revolution they didn't want the Jesus
that overthrew that overthrew the tables
in the temple they wanted a Jesus that
would overthrow the tables in the
government they wanted a Jesus that
would get rid of their political foes
they wanted a Jesus that would get rid
of the Gentile the unbeliever the
ungodly that's what they were after and
here's what they did they looked at the
character of Barabas
they knew he was a murderer they knew he
was corrupt they knew all those things
but they were like but you know
what right
now character can get a
pass yet no our Jesus doesn't need to be
loving and kind and merciful in fact
that's we want a John Wayne type of
Jesus we we want a we want a Jesus that
is rough
tough blast your enemies mock your
foes we want that kind of a
Jesus that's what they were after that's
what they were looking
for so so they end up
choosing
Barabas the Bible tells us in Acts 3:13
the god of Abraham and Isaac and Jacob
the god of our fathers has glorified his
son Jesus whom you delivered up and
denied in the presence of pilate when he
when he was determined to let him go but
you denied the Holy One and the just and
desired a murderer to be granted unto
you and killed the Prince of Life whom
God has raised from the dead whereof we
Are
Witnesses listen to
me the Jesus they chose
was a Jesus of their
imagination the the Jesus that the
Believers
chose in the days of Jesus was a Jesus
that was after their own
Hearts we like you because you are like
us that's what they wanted that's what
they were
after listen to me
what is the
matter with mystery Babylon now who is
Mystery Babylon that is the power that
the Bible describes in the Book of
Revelation as an end time power that has
a mother and then daughters the mother
is the first Beast the papacy the
daughters are what come after her what
is the matter when I say modernday
protestantism why is she called Babylon
mean meaning confusion why is she called
that why are the churches described as
Fallen the reason why beloved is because
the churches have desired another
Jesus they have desired
Barabas they have desired a Jesus that's
not going to tell them that what they're
doing is wrong they just want a Jesus
who will make who they just want of
Jesus who will conquer their
enemies honor their worship and honor
their Nation they want a Jesus that
wants the same thing that they want they
don't want a Jesus that's going to
transform the heart a Jesus that's going
to write the law on their heart in fact
they say no that law is done away with
we don't have to worry about that but
they do want a Jesus who will write that
law in the legislative Halls that's the
Jesus that they
want give us Barabas give us the son of
the father that's what they're asking
for they're saying Hey Y'all we worship
the son of the father but they're
worshiping a different son of the
father are you
following don't think right now oh he's
comparing so no I'm comparing the de the
Barabas to the devil that's what I'm
doing
barabus is the devil counterfeiting as
Jesus but some of us are so
politically
entrenched that all you hear right now
is somebody's
name and you're
offended why because for many of us
politics and our nation has taken the
place of Jesus and we even in our church
have
we have uplifted Barabas instead of
Jesus we are following Barabas instead
of Jesus we like this
Jesus we like this Jesus who is like
yeah man mock your enemies yeah yeah
yeah laugh when you're enemy yeah we
like this Jesus that says we're coming
in with power and Dominion to we like
that Jesus
who would have thought that even in our
church we would no longer be able to
tell the difference between the son of
the father and the son of the
father many of you came here today to
hear me compare Barabas to somebody and
I'm telling you Beloved the Barabas I'm
comparing Barabas to the devil and what
I'm saying is that the devil is a
counterfeit Jesus that has set up an
image of Jesus that many of us have
fallen
for in our minds
Jesus is this way and is for this and is
for that and if you're a Christian you
know that Jesus is this way and
therefore this is what you must do
because this is what Jesus would do
don't you know aren't you a Christian
hey all Christians do it this way
all Christians are against Rome come on
are you D are you really a Christian if
you really a Christian then you know
that we don't like Rome you know that
Rome is the enemy you know when Jesus
was like no the enemy is right here in
the church the enemy that's why I'm
flipping tables in the church and not
flipping
tables in the government but no no no no
no no that's not the Jesus that
modern-day Christianity wants so check
this out y'all let let's go back and
read a few statements here uh spirit of
Prophecy volume 3 and Page 405 listen to
this but for some time they had been
growing arrogant and insubordinate and
after that they had rejected and
crucified Christ the light of the world
they followed their own darkened
understanding manifested more openly
their their envy and hatred of the
powers that govern them and proudly
boasted of a king of the Jews who was to
come with great power overthrow their
enemies and establish a magnificent
Kingdom it was in view of this vague
belief that they had rejected the Savior
wow
wow they thought they thought it was a
virtue to talk about openly their hatred
for the G for the
Jews their hatred for the Marx their
hatred for the Romans I'm sorry their
hatred for the Romans yes yes yes their
hatred for the RO they thought it was a
virtue to talk about their hatred for
the
Godless they were like yeah we want a
king that's going to deal with the
infiltration of the Godless the Godless
are getting into our schools and the
Godless are getting into our government
and the Godless are getting into into
into our entertainment and into our
media and the and never mind the Godless
godlessness that was going on in their
hearts no no no no no that's not a big
deal let's deal with the godlessness out
there so now we don't want you Jesus we
want
Jesus we don't want you son of the
father we want this son of the father
let's keep
reading the same malignant spirit that
actuated them in their persecution of
the Son of God LED them to rebel against
the Roman government stop right there
hold up wait a
minute wait what
The Same Spirit the same malignant
Spirit the same satanic spirit that
actuated them in their persecution of
the Son of God LED them to rebel against
the Roman government is has Ellen White
lost her
mind how can rebelling against the Roman
government be wrong
Ellen come on the Roman government is
out to get us the Roman government is
out the Roman government all these
things about the Roman government but
she says that the same satanic spirit
that led them to reject Jesus is the
same satanic spirit that led them to
rebel against the Roman
government let's keep reading let's go
back to the screen they were
continually
creating
seditions and insurrection what was
Barabas doing what was he in jail for
sedition and what
insurrections
H they were continually creating
seditions and insur insurrections until
they were finally driven from Rome
because of their turbulent
Spirit
wow wow
desire Ages page
3:10 the Jews cultivated a spirit of
retaliation in their hatred of the
Romans they gave utterance to hard
denunciations and pleased the wicked one
by manifesting his
attributes thus they were training
themselves to do the terrible Deeds to
which he led them on Wow do y'all see
this this thing of
rejoicing in hating your
enemy in rejoicing of hating the
government in rejoicing of hating the
global Elites and and and and mocking
and laughing when you get a victory this
list listen y'all when when Christians
supposedly get a victory over the world
that
spirit that
spirit is setting up millions of
Christians to receive
barabus when he
comes and I'm not talking about a a
person a human I'm talking about the
ultimate barabus when he comes by
accepting the spirit of barabus now in
the name of
righteousness the spirit of Suspicion
the spirit of anger the spirit of hatred
this this Spirit beloved is is preparing
your heart to resonate with that barabus
the son of the Father the counterfeit
when he appears you will be like man
there's something about this guy that I
just love
he sticks it to
him he's not Mambi
pambi there's something about him he
just he's not like everybody he's he
gives it to
him and he's not ashamed to do it he'll
speak out boldly and he'll Mock and
he'll like yeah that's who that's who I
that's the Barabas that's the Barabas
y'all y'all don't y'all don't get it man
the devil is playing chess
while many of y'all are playing
checkers the devil is playing chess
while the Christian world is playing
checkers I I it it it it blows my mind
how many of us are preparing are
receiving the Barabas Spirit In The Name
of
righteousness in the name of Truth
Listen to me let's go back to desire
Ages page 310 in the religious life of
the Pharisees there was nothing to
recommend piety to the Gentiles Jesus B
them not to deceive themselves with the
thought that they could in heart rise up
against their oppressors and cherish the
longing to avenge their wrongs do y'all
see this do y'all see this this is
something that is clearly ignored in
today's
Christianity she goes on to say hatred
of the Romans and National and spiritual
Pride led the Jews to still adhere
rigorously to their forms of worship the
priests tried to maintain a reputation
for sanctity by scrupulous attention to
the ceremonies of religion the people in
their darkness and oppression and the
rulers thirsting for power longed for
the coming of one who would Vanquish
their enemies and restore the kingdom of
America
they had studied in the
prophecies but without spiritual
Insight thus they overlooked the
scriptures that point to the humiliation
of Christ's first Advent and misapplied
those that speak of the glory of his
second Pride obscured their Vision they
interpreted prophecy in accordance with
their selfish
[Music]
desires listen to
this the SP spirit this is a total
different place now letters and
manuscripts Volume
14 the spirit which in Christ's day led
the priests and the rulers to forbid the
recognition of Christ as the scent of
God is alive today and is forbidding men
to accept the word of God just as it
reads the Christ they would receive must
be one who would intensify their hatred
for the Romans and exalt the Jewish na
all right
y' I don't have a I only have like this
kind of mic on me so I can't drop it it
wouldn't make any
noise but I need y'all to see
this the Christ they would receive must
be one who would intensify their hatred
for the Romans and exalt the Jewish
Nation do you realize beloved that
today this is exactly what you are
seeing in Evangelical Christian
Christianity Evangelical
Christianity needs a
Jesus that excuses their hatred for the
enemy the gays the lesbians the
immigrants who are coming in to take
their place the illegal immigrants the
the the the murderers H H uh the the
cultural marxists the the the woke crowd
uh um the the the the the transgender
crowd the and here's a crazy thing
here's a crazy thing that as I'm saying
this stuff people will take this and be
like see he's he's down with the
transgender he's down with the with the
he's down with the with the Marxist he's
down with the because he's he's he's not
talking about them he's talking about
the Christian
church do you realize this is the same
spirit that put Jesus to
death Jesus why aren't you spending more
time
talking about the Romans the Gentiles
why Jesus why do you keep pointing out
our sins Jesus we're tired of you we're
going to put you on a
cross the Jesus they wanted was one that
must exalt their Nation their national
pride and condemn others that's the
Jesus we
want and if you're not willing to do
that Jesus then we're not trying to hear
you we need another Jesus we need a
Barabas and that's exactly what modern
day Christianity that's exactly who
modern day Christianity is worshiping
today now I know many of you upset I
know y'all were looking for a sound bite
where I said a candidate was Barabas and
therefore the other candidate must be
Jesus I know I already saw the comments
in the in the chat when I posted the oh
he's going to say I know what yall
looking
for listen
y'all the
sooner we get our
heads out of the political
brainwash and start thinking prophecy
again the moment everything will be all
right with
us the moment everything will be all
right with us
that's the
moment so many of us
slept that what's happening
now you don't even know how to look at
it we weren't supposed to Win It was
supposed to be a liberal takeover it was
supposed to be a Marxist takeover it was
we we've been saying all along it's
going to be a communist and the
government is going to and now y'all be
like oh this is a reprieve God has given
us a little bit more time that's how we
that's how it's going to
forget about what the Bible says about a
prostate protestantism we're going to be
like oh God is giving us more
time it's almost like whatever we can do
to
protect the idea of national
pride and a Jesus who rejoices in US
defeating the ungodly a Jesus that
rejoices and US rejoicing over our
enemies that's it that's we need to keep
that thing
going because our own
hearts are in actuality like
that we want a rough
Jesus so come on I'm about to break this
down and then we're going to end then
listen a lot of y'all are not going to
like this but we got we have to go here
we have to go here I'm I I refuse to to
protect apostate Christianity this
doesn't mean that all Christians are
apostate there have been good Christians
beloved since the founding of this
country there have been beautiful Godly
Christians that have
done what Jesus would want them to
do but on the other hand please listen
to me y'all on the other
hand the
church has been worshiping a Jesus
that is
Barabas from it apostate protestantism
has been worshiping a barabus come on
let me show you let me show you then
we're going to wrap this up selected
messages book three page 415 some of
y'all going to need to pray some of
y'all going to need to pray because y
going to twist this to to to the but you
know what do what you will with it
listen the scenes of of the Betrayal of
uh the scenes of the Betrayal rejection
and crucifixion of Christ have been re
acted and will again be reenacted on an
immense scale people will be filled with
the attributes of Satan the delusion of
the Ark enemy of God and man will have
great
power those who have given their
affections to any leader but
Christ those who have given their
affections to any leader but Christ
those who have given their affection to
any leader but
Christ those who have given their
affection to any leader but
Christ will find themselves under the
control Body Soul and Spirit of an
infatuation that is so
entrancing that it's that under its
power Souls turn away from hearing the
the truth to believe a lie they are ens
snared and taken and by their every
action they
cry release unto us
Barabas but
crucify
Christ are y'all good
let's go back to the
screen let's go back to the
screen select the messages book 3 page
416 in the churches which have departed
from the truth and righteousness it is
being revealed that human nature will
bend and do it is being revealed what
human nature will be and do when the
love of God Is Not An abiding principle
in the soul we need not be surprised at
anything that may take place now we need
not Marvel at any develop M of
Horrors those who trample under their
Unholy feet the law of God have the same
Spirit as had the men who insulted and
betrayed Jesus without any compunction
of conscience they will do the Deeds of
their
father so let's talk about Dragon
speak let's talk about the church having
Barabas
as their
Jesus during the 17 and
1800s many Christians had
Barabas as their
Jesus as they
could say yeah I worship Jesus but the
Jesus I
worship allows me
to have
slaves
and back
slavery that's my
Jesus and this is not just a Christian
here or there this was Christianity in
America by and large now praise God that
there were other Christians who were
following Jesus and who knew yeah that's
not the real Jesus that's what rabas
y'all are
following but for the most part
Christianity chose Barabas they chose
Barabas in fact in early writings page
274 the Bible sorry in early writings
page 274 Ellen White says I'm sorry
about that Ellen White says I saw that
since Jesus left the holy place of the
Heavenly sanctuary and entered within
the second Veil now listen to this she's
talking about when Jesus moved from holy
to most holy and look at what she
connects with that
action I saw saw that since Jesus left
the holy place of the Heavenly sanctuary
and entered within the second Veil the
churches have been filling up with every
unclean and hateful bird I saw great
iniquity and vess in the churches yet
their members profess to be Christians
keep reading their professions their
prayers and their exhortations are an
abomination in the sight of God said the
Angel God will not smell in their
assemblies selfishness fraud and deceit
are practiced by them without their
reproving of
conscience all and all over these evil
traits they throw the cloak of religion
I was sown the pride of the nominal
churches God is not in their thoughts
their carnal Minds dwell upon themselves
they decorate their poor mortal bodies
and then and then look upon themselves
with sanctification and pleasure Jesus
and the angels look upon them in Anger
said the angel their sins and pride have
reached unto Heaven their portion is
prepared Justice and judgment have
slumbered long but will soon awake
vengeance is mine I will repay say the
Lord the fearful threatenings of the
third Angel are to be realized and all
the wicked are to drink of the wrath of
God and innumerable hosts of evil angels
are spreading over the whole land and
crowding the churches these agents of
Satan look upon the religious bodies
with exaltation for the cloak of
religion covers the greatest crime and
iniquity listen y'all all heaven beholds
with indignation human beings the
workmanship of God reduced by their
fellow men to the lowest depths of
degradation and placed on a level with
brute creation professed followers of
that D savior whose compassion was ever
moved at the sight of human woe heartily
engaged in this enormous and Grievous
sin and deal in slaves and Souls of men
men a reference to Revelation 18
describing Babylon human Agony is
carried from place to place and bought
and sold angels have recorded it it is
written in the book The Tears of the
pious bondman and Bond woman of fathers
mothers and children brother and sisters
are bottled up in heaven God will
restrain his anger but little longer his
wrath Burns against this nation and
especially against the religious bodies
that have sanctioned this terrible
traffic and have themselves engaged in
it such Injustice such oppression such
sufferings are looked upon with
heartless indifference by many professed
followers of the meek and lowly Jesus
many of them can themselves inflict with
hateful satisfaction all this
Indescribable Agony and yet dare to
worship God it is Solemn mockery Satan
exalts s over it and reproaches Jesus
and his angels with such inconsistency
saying with hellish Triumph such are the
followers of
Christ all right
y'all I know what you're saying well
Pastor uh that was in the8 1700s and 18
1800s but Babylon has since gotten
better the Fallen churches have since
gotten better don't you know can't you
see I mean yeah it was Babylon back then
but you know not any
longer slavery was outlawed in the
1860s all right come on let's go back to
the screen let's see if these Fallen
churches continue with their dragon
speak yeah so there was a Jim Crow
error y'all know that error
right from the 1870s all the way up to
the
1960s
laws against but Christ this is the
Christian church now praise God there
were Christians in in in in the United
States of America thank God for America
because there were Christians who had
the freedom to stand up and fight
against such oppression and did so not
only during slavery but even in the Jim
Crow era so praise God for the
Christians who are following Jesus but
not praise God for the Christians who
are following
Barabas who had barabus as their
Jesus are y'all following
me even in these Fallen systems and in
these Fallen churches there were genuine
Christians who were following the real
Jesus look at what Ellen White has to
say about this era there is a terrible
crisis just before us through which all
must pass and especially will it come
will it come and be felt in blank my
mind has been much troubled over the
positions which some of our Brethren are
liable to take in regard to the work to
be done among the colored people in the
southern states so slavery has been
abolished now you can do work for the
southern people in the States but it's a
Jim Crow
error and notice what she says there is
one point I wish to lay before those who
work in the southern field among the
colored people they will have to labor
in different lines from those followed
in the north why
why they cannot go to the South and
present the real facts in reference to
Sunday keeping being the mark of the
beast and and encourage the color people
to work on Sunday for the Same Spirit
that held the colored people in slavery
is not dead but alive
today and ready to spring into Activity
The Same Spirit of of Oppression is
still cherished in the minds of many of
the white people of the South and will
reveal itself in Cruel Deeds which are
the manifestation of their
religious
Zeal some will oppos in every possible
way any action that has a tendency to
uplift the colored race and teach them
to be self-supporting so let's come back
to the screen for a moment let's come
back to the screen for a moment and and
I just want you to
know that
yeah these were Christians who were
following
Barabas who were following
Barabas who thought yeah
segregation that should be our
thing we will not intermingle with black
people they can't be in our
schools the lynchings the Jim cral all
of
that
promoted
promoted by the Fallen churches by
Babylon I need yall to understand
beloved when you reject the law of God
when you say the law of God is done away
with the door is open for you to to to
to act any way and justify it in the
name of
Christianity and so what we see in the
history of the American of the churches
in America the the churches in American
history is their ability to hold on to
Jesus while also holding on to slavery
but it wasn't Jesus Jesus you understand
it was Jesus Barabas it wasn't Jesus
Jesus it was Jesus
Barabas and so you say well Pastor
beginning in the 1970s that's when you
know uh when when 1960s passed and yes
you know everything was desegregated
that's when the Babylonian churches then
began to really become nice again but no
no no you guys you got to follow the
prophecy the prophecy is not condemning
people it's condemning A system that
allows you to remain hypocrite critical
and accept the Jesus that is a barabus
instead of the real Jesus that would
actually transform your
heart so yes now now what we have is in
the 1970s and the 1980s you now have
this rise of this movement called the
religious right why because they were
angry that the government came in and
told them you must desegregate your
schools so
now with Barabas at the head they're
like nah n now we we need to take this
political thing into our we need a Jesus
that is going to go into the government
and overturn tables we need to gather
together a voting block that's going to
that is going to stop the government
from coming into into our states our
cities and telling us what we can do and
what we can't do we need to start H uh
sending our people into the government
so that we can we can save ourselves
from the enemies of Marxism and
communism because it's really just
communism that came in to talk about to
to to push this desegregation this whole
movement was a communist movement and so
we're going to start talking about the
dangers of Communism and the dangers of
government getting in and telling you
what you can't do all because they told
us yeah yeah yeah you can't segregate
any longer and we have the right we're
going to start our own homeschooling
system in the name of
Barabas and now we understand we need to
if we don't do something our place and
our nation are going to be taken
away by the
ungodly by the
others many Christians don't understand
this
history they
don't but praise God that there are many
Christians who can I Christians in these
Fallen churches who have said n Ah
that's barabus right there that that's
not the Jesus of the
Bible the Jesus of the Bible is not
trying to get us the Jesus of the Bible
is not trying to get us to go overtake
the government the Jesus of the
Bible wants us to go and win
Hearts not seats in the
Congress to win
Hearts not seats in the House to win
Hearts not positions in the government
that's
Barabas Barabas says I got you I'll go
into the
government I'll be the Jesus that tells
you to overthrow the government I'll be
the Jesus of sedition I'll be the Jesus
that's going to fight for every vote
I'll be the Jesus that does and so
what's the matter with modern day
Christianity the the matter with modern
day Christianity Today everyone is this
they have a Jesus that is not Jesus this
Jesus's last name is Barabas meaning
they have a Jesus that is a
counterfeit they have a Jesus that
doesn't worry about the law written on
their heart this Jesus tells them that
law is done away with you don't need to
keep the Sabbath you don't need to keep
the law of God it's done away with
you're under the New Covenant you're
under grace oh by the way even though
you're under grace the law is for the
wicked so um let's put the law in the
government but y'all don't need to keep
it y'all don't need to be honest y'all
don't need to be be sincere y'all don't
need to be converted y'all don't need to
to actually be Godly and and as such
yeah you can use ungodly means and
ungodly methods and you can lie and you
can do whatever you need to do to get
the right people into and by the way
don't worry about their characters you
know what I mean character who cares
about what God cares about is
government that's what he really wants
he wants us to conquer the governments
for
him yes a fake
Jesus now why is this important to
understand y'all here's
why because the Bible
prophesies that at the end of time a
counterfeit Jesus is
coming a Jesus is coming that will
pretend to be the actual Jesus but will
actually be Barabas
and when this barabus comes he's coming
saying I am setting up a new
kingdom the headquarters of which will
be
America I am coming to to usher in a
reign of righteousness A Reign of peace
and all of you Christians who've been
fighting the good fight and you've been
getting the vote out and you've been
conquering in the government I'm here to
tell you that you've done a good job you
have conquered the seven
mountains and all those who don't go
along with you all those those who are
who are the the ungodly the global
Elites the the the the vaccine pushers
who are trying to kill you off the the
the the woke mob the all of those they
will now bow and worship at your feet
and for those who don't
that's
blasphemy in a theocracy like
this and let me tell
you if that Jesus were to come
today do you understand how many people
would cheer for that
Jesus because they have been conditioned
to do so
now do you know how many people would be
like get him
Jesus yes let's
go something in their hearts will
resonate with the heart of
Satan because little by little they were
trained by the things of This
World by the Spirit of this
world to accept a
barabus instead of a
Jesus there is a reason why the Bible
says come out of her my
people that you be not partakers of her
plagues I
doubt that the crowd in Jesus's day
would have ever thought when Jesus was
healing and and blessing them that they
would have ever thought that a day could
come where
they would cry
out give us Barabas I doubt that any of
them ever saw that day coming but guess
what it
came and there they were convicted as
ever that barabus was the right man for
Israel Lord have
mercy May our
eyes be
open to the deception
of the enemy May our eyes be
open to the prophecies that God has
given us to warn us of what is
coming May our eyes be
open to the sad
reality that most people that reject
Christianity is because they are seeing
barabus as the Jesus of Christianity
instead of the real Jesus as the Jesus
of
Christianity the world out there
knows that whoever this is that
Evangelical Christians are worshiping
today it cannot
be the Jesus of the Bible
my simple appeal to you
today if you're an Evangelical
Christian I ask you to go back and read
the
Bible and
see if the Jesus that you see being
pushed in the political
field in evangelicalism
today is actually Jesus or is it
Barabas if you're an Adventist
that has unfortunately found
yourself worshiping
Barabas instead of the Jesus of the
Bible I pray that today you will say
Lord I Repent forgive me I knew not what
I was
doing and if you're someone today who's
watching Adventist or or or not and
you're just saying
Lord I believe I'm following Jesus
Jesus I don't think I have that spirit
and help me to not have anything in me
that would draw me to a
barabus to a false
Christ keep my soul lord preserve me
that I may be like
you then you put that one in the chat
you raise your hand do what you need to
do but
beloved let us be followers of
Jesus and not followers of
Barabas that is my
prayer in Jesus
name amen heavenly
father thank you for speaking to
us thank you for opening our
eyes and Lord right now I want to pray
for those who are watch this message and
hear
[Music]
nothing except through a political
lens and will miss this
message and totally missed the point
Lord prevent that from
happening remove the devil's
delusions and please Lord
save
us not
from other people save us from the
deceitfulness of our own
Hearts thank you Lord for hearing an
answering this
prayer because we ask it in Jesus
name amen
and amen may God bless you um as you
meditate upon this word we're going to
go ahead and put the uh alter live Link
in the chat for those of you that would
like to join us in the after glow in the
after
discussion and uh may God may God bless
you share this message y share this
message with those who need to hear it
and uh may God bless you and may God
keep you and uh I will see you again
next Sabbath by God's grace Grace
blessings thank you for joining us today
if this is your first time worshiping
with us please check out our website at
Living mana. Church we are not just here
for Sabbath service we have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health physical health weekly prayer
service Financial Health and proving the
existence of God it is our desire that
our programming will continue to bless
you please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the Gospel of Jesus Christ
[Music]